# Soumya Veer

• San Mateo, CA • (832) 803-6200 • veer.soumya@gmail.com • github.com/soumyaveer • soumyathinks.com •

#### **SUMMARY**

An analytical, hard working full stack web developer with a passion for learning. I am experienced in Ruby, JavaScript, SQL and have a background in Electrical Engineering. I want to use my problem-solving skills and technology to solve interesting problems.

## **SKILLS**

Object oriented programming using Ruby and JavaScript. Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, React, SQL, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.

# **PROJECTS**

### Trivia Zone

Trivia Zone is a fun way to test your knowledge and compete with others online.

- Uses Ruby on Rails and Postgres on the backend.
- Uses JQuery, Bootstrap and custom CSS on the frontend.
- Uses Devise and OmniAuth for Facebook OAuth authentication.
- Deployed on Heroku.

#### Reminders

The Reminders app helps you manage important tasks by scheduling them via email notifications.

- Uses Ruby on Rails as the backend API server.
- · Uses React, Redux, React Router on the frontend.
- Deployed on Heroku.

### **Book Progress**

Book Progress helps you track your reading progress and watch what others are reading.

- Uses Sinatra and Postgres on the backend.
- Uses CSS, Bootstrap on the frontend.
- Uses a custom signup and authentication system written from scratch.
- · Deployed on Heroku.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Math Tutor

## University of Houston

June 2014—May 2015, Houston, Texas

Taught undergraduate students algebra, geometry, business calculus, and other Math related undergraduate courses.

## Systems Engineer

## Infosys, Ltd.

November 2009—October 2012, Pune, India

- Developed SQL queries to interact with the Oracle billing databases.
- Automated the execution of SQL queries used to generate reports.
- Worked on the production support team to perform diagnosis of bugs and failures in the Bank of America production applications.

## **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School

July 2018—Present

Taught undergraduate students algebra, geometry, business calculus, and other Math related under graduate courses.

#### University of Houston

August 2013-May 2015, Houston, Texas

• Degree: M.S. in Electrical Engineering. GPA 3.6

# Visveswaraiah Technological University

Degree: BE. in Electronics and Communications Engineering. GPA 3.6

August 2005—May 2009, Bangalore, India